# **GRANT AMMONS**

+1215-801-7554

grant@grant.dev

https://grant.dev

grant-ammons

I'm an engineering leader and software engineer with over 15 years of experience building web-based applications at scale, and supporting the people that build them. I'm seeking a leadership role at a product-focused, high growth company.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Head of Engineering @ ConvertKit - Jan 2017 - Oct 2020

ConvertKit is a growing SaaS email marketing company that caters towards creators. I joined when we were at approximately \$6M in ARR, and I helped scale it to nearly \$25M.

- Coached, mentored, and led a team of 26, and directly managed 4 engineering managers and 2 SREs.
- **Built + matured processes** hiring, software delivery, QA, performance reviews / promotions, and others. Obtained <u>near 100% uptime</u> of all services over the course of 2 years.
- **Built a strong Devops culture** and obtained <u>Elite performance</u> for CI/CD, MTTR, and other application health performance metrics, without sacrificing quality.
- **Built effective team structures** to provide continual value in key areas of ConvertKit's product, and focused on building an efficient, effective software delivery process.
- **Helped scale the architecture** and infrastructure to handle nearly 1B email sends / month, as well as managing click, open, and delivery events in realtime.
- Responsible for formulation + monitoring of \$1M+ annual engineering budget. Kept production infrastructure costs below 4% of revenue.

# VP Engineering / Co-founder @ Pipeline Deals - January 2007 - October 2017

PipelineDeals is a bootstrapped SaaS CRM product that I established with 2 other co-founders. During the time I was there, I helped build it from an idea to a full-fledged CRM product serving thousands of customers with over \$6M ARR.

- Coached, mentored, and led 15 remote software engineers, broken into 3 teams.
- **Established effective software delivery process** to ensure high quality and tight collaboration.
- **Ensured best practices** for software delivery. Implemented continuous delivery via blue/green deployment setup and custom feature flipper that allows us to keep feature branches short and small.
- Managed a large production infrastructure in AWS, overseeing 50+ server instances. Implemented best-in-class practices to ensure speed, scalability, and uptime. Achieved 99.999% uptime in 2015. Kept infrastructure costs 5x below SaaS averages by strategic use + planning of reserved instances.
- **Sole engineer on the team** in the early stages, using engineering + DevOps best practices to build features quickly and gain traction.

# Senior Software Engineer @ Revolution Health - 2006

Revolution Health was Steve Case's stealth healthcare startup based in Washington DC.

- Joined a high-performing team that eventually left to form LivingSocial.
- Worked with the Rails team to help rewrite the software from Java to Rails.

# **Senior Software Engineer** @ Hammer Communications - 2005-2006

- Helped design team with all technical aspects of client work.
- Designed a deployment system that managed dozens of websites for clients.

# **ORGANIZATIONS & PROJECTS**

## Chapter co-founder @ CTO School Philadelphia - 2015-present

CTO School is a meetup group of engineering leaders who want to level up their technical leadership skills. The group now has over 250 members. I manage coordinating each monthly event, as well as finding speakers and sponsors. We usually get between 20 and 40 people to show up for the monthly meetup.

#### **Ultradeck** 2016-2018

<u>Ultradeck</u> was a SaaS product I created for engineers to quickly create beautiful slide decks. It did not gain traction, but I did learn an enormous amount about product development and marketing.

- Storybook is <u>still online</u> showing the breadth of the app.
- Utilized create-react-app, Typescript, Redis, Mysql, and Rails.

## **Ultralist** 2018-present

<u>Ultralist</u> is an open source, command-line task management app written in Go. Utilizes Go, websockets for real-time communication, Rails Mysql, create-react-app, and Progressive Web App fundamentals.

## **AWARDS**

ConvertKit's MVP award 2019

## **EDUCATION**

# B.S. Info Systems Technology

**Drexel University** - 2002

#### LEADERSHIP SKILLS

- Empathy
- Servant leadership
- Hiring
- Budget management
- Process building / optimization

#### **ENGINEERING SKILLS**

- Ruby/Rails
- Mysql
- React
- Docker/Kubernetes
- DevOps best practices
- Golang